{
    "id": "ac9551227b6b49c8b32f089509884a2a",
    "title": "Conjunctions Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "I am certain …………………….. you have made a mistake.",
            "description": "We use that to introduce a noun clause. ",
            "answers": [
                "whether",
                "that",
                "of"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "8a76b3be161e45b49cc7e3a7149c0a3c"
        },
        {
            "question": "……………………….. he got the telegram, he left in a taxi.",
            "description": "No sooner should be followed by than. ",
            "answers": [
                "No sooner",
                "As soon as",
                "As long as"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "721078aea3fc4bacab66db8995078626"
        },
        {
            "question": "He worked hard ………………………….. he might win the first prize.",
            "description": "We use the conjunction so that to introduce purpose. Hence is not a conjunction. ",
            "answers": [
                "such that",
                "so that",
                "hence"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "01deebcabd264f4da46087b0a349122a"
        },
        {
            "question": "…………………………. he is at home, we will see him.",
            "description": "We use if to introduce a conditional clause. ",
            "answers": [
                "If",
                "Whether",
                "That"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "9c0071b497a6409783b20b67cc2dab8b"
        },
        {
            "question": "He was buried near Rome in a place ………………………….. myrtles grow.",
            "description": "We can use where to introduce adverb clauses of place.",
            "answers": [
                "there",
                "where",
                "when"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "e4fc9d67c62d4341a88406a23cd64724"
        },
        {
            "question": "The archers were poorly armed ……………………….. they offered a stubborn resistance.",
            "description": "We use but to connect two contrasting ideas.",
            "answers": [
                "and",
                "but",
                "hence"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "e36e60c8ca5147d89e8d911dbb23745b"
        },
        {
            "question": "He lost more …………………………. he could afford.",
            "description": "We use than after a comparative expression.",
            "answers": [
                "then",
                "than",
                "as"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "29283db70dda49dea6bf6e25e79d6245"
        },
        {
            "question": "…………………………. you do not hurry, you will miss the train.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "If",
                "Unless",
                "Without"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "7e13a16425da4f0fbd0e231dbc90b73a"
        },
        {
            "question": "………………………… we do our work sincerely, our master will be angry with us.",
            "description": "Unless is similar to if not.",
            "answers": [
                "If",
                "Unless",
                "Without"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "ea75015bec2e405aa99bccc34f383484"
        },
        {
            "question": "Once upon a time a man owned a hen ………………………….. laid a golden egg every day.",
            "description": "Either which or that can be used to refer to animals, birds or things. ",
            "answers": [
                "that",
                "which",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "5964f64cc8584d54baadd8d8e99c382b"
        },
        {
            "question": "Be diligent …………………………… you will succeed.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "and",
                "or",
                "therefore"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "1d9e5a2d57cd4a9db5a591160a23238f"
        },
        {
            "question": "He ran away ……………………….. he was afraid.",
            "description": "We use because to introduce the reason. ",
            "answers": [
                "so",
                "therefore",
                "because"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "6e119679e64d42ceb34dd9ba0f0eea65"
        }
    ]
}